Heat. Heat. N.
Hey, hey, hey.
[Music]
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome to the latest episode, the
253rd episode of the Ask Kabida show.
Hope everyone's doing great and let us
see who all is there on the live chat.
Let me see. Let me greet greet you all.
Man and bike GK Kulpip Chawan uh Jitesh
Bhardwaj Info King Una Bunga Samarati
Vin Esman Pachit Agarwal Anand Chandak
Geopolitic Dubai from Indor Prenal from
Kolkata Kumar Kanish MM Papu Pizza uh
Subramana De
Vakonda Shankit Adman
uh who else we have Rahu Rahul Dak and
who else do we Vinay esman again. Abham
Chryalla Anu Deepta Bonjour Khal Bay
Capil Singh Love Achara Putin Samatriati
uh Sumitagarwal Sel Sharma Nishant Ti
Anand Chandak um event countdown mlevin
God was alive Suraj Binit Abhishek
Shivastav Kaizen 007 Hunter Kenway Sam
Kapalin Harsh Kapoor Duvya GK who else
do we have Shri Ramachandra Maha Uh Prul
Ra BG BCG Saranga Ninlay Nutan Roshan
Vnav VI Watermelon Wkada Kalbearov Kapil
Singh Love Achara who else? Tanmay
Chakraorti Ankita Goautami Aoto Satapati
Prit Agarwal Harsh Kapoor Bri Amit
Jooshi Rohan Vinod Omar Omar Kamikar
Prul Ra Shin Ramchandraan Naha again uh
Sarang Dinali who else uh Nishad Nishant
Mohit Yashika Spade Tanoy and everybody
else all right thank you so much all of
you for being on live stream. I really
appreciate that. We'll take some
questions as many as Quen as we can in
the next hour or
so. And let's get going. I will first
take the super chats and then if they
get over in this still more time, I'll
take other chats as well. So, let's go
with utkash lats to have max impact on
500 to in
500 50 to 100 years economic cultural
objectives. Where should I put money as
a donor as an investor? any specific
sectors, companies, organizations. Look,
it depends on how much money you want to
put. If you want to have a real impact,
then you got to put uh millions, maybe
billions of dollars. So, if you are a
donor as as if you're an investor, I
would I would recommend you first invest
wherever the return on investment is the
highest and let the money grow. Let the
money grow and then when you have
substantial amounts of money, you can
invest it somewhere. If you want
economic cultural objectives,
um, if you want economic growth for
India and cultural growth for India,
where would you
invest as an investor, right? That's a
good question. Let's say I, let's say I
have a billion dollars. What would I do?
Um, I would probably not think as an
investor, as an investor. I would think
as a philanthropist. I may start a
university of my own in which I would
have things taught the right way. I
would do that. Uh what would I do? I
would I
would I would fund temples perhaps. I
would fund a world yoga standards
institute. What would I do? I would I
would uh maybe if I had a billion
dollars, maybe more than that, I would
start an Indian version of SpaceX. So
these are the things I would do. Now if
you obviously I'm sure you don't have a
billion dollars here but if you were to
invest some money maybe you can invest
in some something along the same lines
but I'm not sure what return on
investment you'll get as a consequence.
I I said that I am thinking not as an
investor I'm thinking as a
philanthropist right now. Of course if
you start a successful company like
SpaceX it's that's not a philanthropic
work that's that's that's good
entrepreneurreneurial work.
So yeah, it depends. It depends on so
many factors. Um I would say that that
put money wherever your heart is
aligned. But if you want to think as an
investor, I would say first of all, put
put money where there's going to be the
best possible return on investment. Then
when you have more money, then you can
do something like this. That's what I
would say. Udb Sharma says, as for your
analysis, do you suspect are the members
of the actual deep state of the US? Why
doesn't Bat or India have
it? See every every nation has an extra
electoral extra democratic center of
power. But in a weak nation you have a
weak weak deep state. In India you have
people who are powerful without being
part of the system. Right? Without being
elected there are people who are
powerful. They in India they what in
Bollywood they call them king makers and
all that. And there are some people who
are super rich who have inherited money
from the British
times the days of the British
occupation. So those you can say are
India's deep state. But are they aligned
with India's national interest? I'm not
quite sure. So India doesn't have
it. Now is the so-called deep state of
the US aligned with the US national
interest? I'm not sure about that also.
Maybe the US itself is a tool they are
using for global domination. That sort
of thing. So who do I suspect are the
members of the actual deep state of the
US? Yeah. People with really old money
perhaps. H whoever is
the stakeholders shareholders of the
Federal Reserve Bank and we don't quite
know who they are. Of course the Federal
Reserve we said will say that you know
other banks are our stakeholders and so
on so forth. It's a very very
complicated web of obfuscation but
whoever is behind all this is the
members of possibly the deep members of
the deep state. Who are they? Can I name
them? I don't know the names. So can't
say that's why it's hidden. Otherwise if
if if I would know about it then how
will it be hidden right it's got to stay
hidden Kumar Kaneska says what would
what could be the reason for the past
incident especially the condition the
bodies were found avalanche can't be the
reason can this be a USSR cover up so
there's this very fascinating incident
that happened sometime in the 1960s a
bunch of hikers went into some Siberian
pass called the Datlov pass the leader
of the group was his surname was Datloff
and then they disappeared and then later
their bodies are found in very strange
conditions you It was freezing weather,
snow everywhere, but they were found
with their undergarments on and some
people had organs missing and some
absolutely weird stuff was there and uh
yeah, so there's no explanation. No
one's been able to explain what happened
and there have been rumors of uh
supernatural causes and alien abduction
kind of activity and so on. Uh so what
could be the reason? I have absolutely
no idea. It's a mystery. That's the
reason it's a mystery. It's definitely
really fascinating, very mysterious,
kind of creepy, kind of scary. And I
don't know what happened. Maybe aliens
came there because there are no
footprints of somebody who did something
violent to these people which caused
their deaths. There's no they could not
find any evidence of a shred of evidence
of other people. So maybe these people
were perhaps killed because they they
discovered some USSR state secrets
perhaps and then the USSR authorities
covered up. That could be a possibility.
But there's no evidence either way.
Whether it's a USSR cover up or it's an
alien abduction or aliens came and did
something or there was some some
supernatural entity. Absolutely no idea.
Big mystery and it's an enduring
mystery. Kumar Karnish says how does
uranium react with dark matter in
research? Uranium is regular matter.
Regular matter doesn't interact with
dark matter. That's the problem. Dark
matter is supposed to be at least cold
dark matter is supposed to be purely
gravitating which means it will not
react at all with any electromagnetic
force object any object that interacts
electromagnetically and uranium is just
regular matter. So there's no
interaction beyond the gravitational
interaction which is super super super
super incredibly weak like 10 tous 30
something orders of magnitude weaker
than the weak force which is shocking.
So no reaction. Mm says, "Your first
beer biceps show changed my life." Thank
you, sir. I moved from manufacturing to
it at 30 by applying first principles
also started running my agency. U Thank
you so much. I it's it's so nice to hear
the these stories. So, I really
appreciate that and thank you so much
for your contribution, sir. I really
appreciate that. And once again, we have
MM who says, "I have a one-year-old
daughter. How can I raise her with
Indian values and high standards
knowledge of Indian history knowing the
conditions of the Indian education
system?" Yeah, that's a great
question. How do you raise your kid with
Indian values and high standards? You
can expose your kids to to to the Rama
and the
Mahabharat ideally in your own mother
tongue. You do that, you spend an hour a
day, half an hour a day, uh going
through this with your kid, you're going
to that kid, the kid will have Indian
values and the kid will have a higher
standard than most kids. And if you want
to have real high standards, you need to
you know
inculcate uh scientific approach in the
kid. Best way is to make sure the kid is
very well grounded in mathematics,
basics of mathematics and understands
science well. If you understand science
well, you automatically will have the
scientific method ingrained in you which
is you know all the all the things that
come with the scientific method, first
principles analysis and so on so forth.
Knowledge of Indian history, well that's
a whole different thing. You need a lot
of reading to know know Indian history
properly and then there's a risk that
you're going to get misled by Indian
history because most of the books have
distortions and kids are just so
trusting it's not their fault they will
read and they'll believe most of the
people in India who are misled by our
historians are completely innocent. It
is not their fault at all. So you can't
see them as enemies. My point is you
know that learning Indian history
properly is it's difficult that takes
time that takes experience but Indian
values Rama and Maharat teach that in
your mother tongue ideally if possible
Sanskrit that's even better uh and and
yeah and and inculcate the scientific
approach that should do it all the best
all the best sir Kumar Kanesh says why
does why is radioactive uranium abundant
on earth compared to other rocky planets
as it is not formed on planets does it
have any relation to the origin of life.
I'm not sure what the origin what the
abundance of uranium is on Venus or on
Mars. I'm not sure we have done any
study cuz we hardly have any access to
Mars. We have a couple of instruments
over there, American instruments. They
are not equipped to search for
radioactivity as far as I'm as as I'm
aware. I'm not sure they're equipped to
search for uranium. So how do we know
that there's more uranium on earth
compared to rocky planets like uh like
Venus or Mars or Mercury? Mercury we
have absolutely no idea. So as far as I
know there's no evidence that we have
more abundance of uranium than Venus or
Mars or
Mercury. Right? So I'm not sure where
you got this information. I am not aware
of this information.
Um now how does uranium form is the
question. It forms in disastrous very
very high
intensity astrophysical events like the
merger of neutron stars. Two neutron
stars collide and merge that sort of
thing. Then you have extremely heavy
elements being formed like gold, lead,
uranium etc. Right? So these uranium
generally forms through these extremely
energetic astrophysical events.
iron etc forms during supernova
explosions or it it is the precursor to
the to a star going supernova and so on
so forth. So the heavy elements they
come into existence through very violent
astro astrophysical events. So we
inherited all this metal or whatever we
have on the planet which came from the
destruction of ancient
stars. The sun our sun is about 4
something billion years old. It is a
second or third generation
star. The gas that it contains, the
hydrogen, mostly hydrogen, 90% plus
hydrogen, it came from other stars that
had gone supernova before it. It's like
the reincarnation of the reincarnation
of a star. That's what the sun is. And
everything on our planet was formed
during supernova explosions or neutron
star
collusions. So the blood, the iron in
our blood, you see the pink in in my
palm, that's iron. That's hemoglobin.
Hemoglobin, it has iron. The iron in our
blood came from a supernova explosion
from the death of a
star and so on. Calcium. Calcium in our
bones. All of that. So that's where we
have it. Uranium is not related to the
origin of life. It's
not. Rohan says, "I hope you uh read my
yesterday comment. Harsh truth by me."
Um I get a million comments a day. I
haven't read your comment. If you had to
tell me a harsh truth, you could have
put it over here instead of putting
this. I I I'll try and look for it.
Okay, I'll try. I I'm not able to read
all the comments. I would love to read
everybody's comments. Believe you me.
Initially, I used to do that when I had
like 10,000 subscribers. I used to read
all the comments. Now it's not possible.
Now, as long as I was taking questions
for Ask Kabijit from the comments, I
used to look at the comments and search
for the Ask Kabijit hashtag. I used to
look for all of those. has to read all
of those like it it would take me hours
but today it's simply impossible. I'm so
sorry. Okay, please don't take it
personally. So if you had to put a
comment you could have put that comment
instead of saying have you read my
comment? You know think logically
sir. Uh anonymous human says maybe a
dumb question. No no no there's no dumb
questions. Please ask. Why doesn't light
have infinite speed? What's stopping it?
It doesn't have mass so technically it
should be infinite. That's just the laws
that have been coded into the fabric of
the universe. Maybe we have a multiverse
and you have other universes with
different speed
limits. So there is
something that has been somehow
predetermined.
See why is the universe the way it is?
We don't know why it is like this. Why
do the universal constants the the
constants the physical constants why do
they have these values? That's a big
gigantic gaping hole in our
understanding of
physics. Why does the gravitational
constant big G have that value? Why is
plank's constant whatever whatever time
10 - 34 whatever word why is it like
that? Why not a different value? Why is
the speed of light so many
m/s? Why is it
that? And and so many other questions.
all the physical constants. You can very
easily Google the list of physical
constants. Shall we do it? Let's do it.
What's the list of physical constants?
I'll give you a whole bunch of examples.
List of
physical constants. Here we have it.
Let's look at an
image. J E good example. Speed of light
plank constant. Um minus Yeah. Why is
the gravitational constant what it is?
Why is the bolt span constant there? Um
why is the charge of the electron
whatever it is in terms of u kulums or
electron walls or whatever. Why is the
kulum's constant what it is? Why is the
stfan bolzman constant what it is? Why
are the constants why do they have these
values? That's a big open question in
physics and we don't have the answers.
So your question is part of that. Why
doesn't light have a different uh speed?
Why is not why is it not
infinite? So well I can give you an
answer from the perspective of
relativity that uh if light has infinite
speed then yeah then you will have
everything will have to have zero mass
and that sort of thing. The point is we
don't know the point is somebody coded
these these constants into our universe.
It's like there was a
programmer okay there was a programmer
who hardcoded these things. If you know
programming you'll know what is hard
coding. It's not a good practice but
somebody hardcoded these parameters into
the universe and we are stuck with them.
Who is this pro programmer? So either
we're living in a simulation or maybe
who knows what
else. Uh Vidic post says what about
Islamic conversions analogous to Joshua
project in India? You mentioned earlier
is there a data I sir I am I don't look
into these matters. I don't look into
matters of religion and religious
strife. I look at geopolitics. I look at
science. I look at history. that's uh
already a huge amount of stuff on my
plate. Uh I cannot fight every battle,
you know. I would love to I would love
to have like three different heads and
three different brains and six arms.
Then I could do all this. But I am not
aware of this. I'm so sorry. I am not
I'm not aware of any data about uh the
quant numbers and uh velocity and
dynamics and whatever of various
conversions to various other outside
religions. Not aware of this. I'm aware
that you know all these things are
happening and it is being
done orchestrated essentially I'm sure
but it's not something I keep keep track
of so I I I don't have the answer to
your question.
Um did I mention Joshua project? I don't
think I've spoken about the Joshua
project either. I'm sure there are lots
of people who discuss these matters and
maybe you thought that I discuss this. I
do not discuss this. I don't discuss
issues of religion. I'll talk about
geopolitics. I'll talk I'm happy to take
talk talk about science. I'm happy to
talk about history. Beyond that, I don't
get into other things. So that's not my
my battle. There are other people, other
warriors who will fight the battle, the
good battle. So you can, you know, look
look into what they have to say. They
they are experts in these things. I have
no idea whatsoever. Sorry about that,
sir. Very sorry. Arun says, "Was she
hassa evil like the students claim?"
What students? Uh the students are
misled. You see, was she necessary evil
which was holding all the bad things of
Bangladesh? So you have fallen victim to
propaganda or maybe you're not victim to
propaganda but you are seeing what the
students are saying. Look students are
what kids right? I was there. How was I
when I was student and a clueless naive
boy. I can look back at myself the way I
was when I was 1920. I was super
clueless about the world. I had a lot of
book
knowledge. I had no real world
experience. Absolute
naive. Everybody at the age of 20 is
like that. At the age of 20, you think
you know everything about the world. But
you're super clueless and super naive.
And it's very easy to mislead young
kids. Young kids as like 18, 19, 20
years old, 20 year olds. So they have
been told Shikas now was this evil
dictator. India is the evil enemy, this
evil Hindu nation. And they want
Bangladesh down. They they are the
enemies of Bangladesh and Shik Kasina
was their puppet. So these students they
believe
it. Is it their fault they believe it?
It's not their fault. It's very easy to
mislead them. So they believe she she
was evil and this this is a great change
for Bangladesh. Mr. Muhammad Yunos the
great Nobel Peace Prize winner. I mean
who can be better than
that? Dr. Muhammad Yunos he is the
Bangladeshi Dr. Manm
Singh. But at least Dr. Man Singh kind
of was elected in some kind of
roundabout
way not really he was a member of the
what Raja Sabha from not from Punjab
from from Assam somewhere I don't know
what what kind of thing it was so yeah
Dr. Muhammad you know is kind of the
Bangladeshi Dr. Mon so look it's very
easy to mislead students she was not
evil what did she do was she elected her
she was elected multiple times by the
people of Bangladesh they claimed the
elections were rigged what evidence do
you have the elections were rigged you
are being rigged so she was not evil my
friends she was not this is all
propaganda which is amplified by the
west by the
way spade says Assar in the previous
stream you said there were there are
nuclear American nuclear warheads in
Pakistan Is that true? I think it's a
possibility. I think there's a non-zero
probability that some of the nuclear
warheads are
American. Okay. I haven't been there. Uh
they haven't invited me and given me
access to check that see see a sar these
are not American warheads. These are
genuine Pakistani warheads. They have
not allowed me to see. So I'm I'm just
using some logic and common sense and
saying that it's possible that the
Americans have given their warheads to
Pakistan as leverage against us. just a
just a hunch and there is a non-zero
probability that this could be true.
Maybe this is there is a 35% probability
that it's the
case in my assessment. Uh Abishek says
where is Elon Musk? Why is he
sidelineed? Who is the deep state? The
deep state is this invisible group of
shadowy people who allegedly run the
world and are the masters and owners of
the United States.
Allegedly. Where is Elon Musk? He is
back in his office either at Tesla or
SpaceX or wherever. He's back among his
minions. He'll launch launch a few more
rockets. Why is he sidelineed? Because
look, he has served his
purpose. Uh foreign policy that
publication they are saying that he was
a useful idiot for Trump. A clown they
call him. The guy who has been
intelligent enough to amass the biggest
fortune in human history according to
foreign policy is a
clown but yeah he's inexperienced in
politics and maybe Trump took him for a
ride so he was used I think Vive Krai
was super intelligent he got out of doge
at the right time and doge doesn't seem
to have made much of an impact and it's
over now so I think Elon Musk is out and
he's back running his companies but he's
you got super deep pockets so he's going
to be useful to Trump is going to remain
useful for Trump for a long long time.
So he's not entirely sidelineed but for
now he's kind of uh no longer in center
stage. All right. He's manticor says the
only way radical abrahamic beliefs can
be damaged or defanged is by good
rational education, excellent per capita
income and removal of blasphemy laws
plus removing all kinds of misguided
funding
thoughts. Once
again question about religion look what
you need in
India is everybody should be taught
India's culture.
No question about
it. Everybody should be should be taught
India's culture and we need to have why
should we not expect to have the world's
best education system. We invented
education, didn't we? We had
universities when the world was
crawling. I mean was was living on
trees. So we need to have good
education. I don't like this word
rational because rational is like you
know the atheistic people in the the
rationalists. There are a bunch of crazy
crackpot loonies who like to use the
word rational everywhere. So I'm kind of
when I see the word rational go whoa
whoa you stay away you you
know rational. I'm so rational. I'm an
atheist. All religions are irrational
and this and that. All religions are the
same. Irrational. So look I don't like
this word rational but I'm I'm sure you
mean it in a good way. Okay? So I'm not
targeting you by the way. Um so we need
good good education. No question about
it. We need highest quality education.
We need education that is focused on
science, technology, education and math.
Uh STEM, right? Whatever the STEM,
science, technology and math, math,
math. Uh that's what we need. And uh we
need everybody to be grounded in Indian
culture, values, morality, ethics and
civilization. And obviously we need high
per capita income. We need good living
standards. We need good uh uh good
governance. We need zero corruption. You
do all those things in India will be
heaven once again. So I agree with you.
What you're saying makes sense.
Yes, Vidimar is asking the same question
again that she asked earlier. Well, it's
okay. I can ask answer you again. Best
source of veg protein without fats and
carbs. No, it's a different question.
It's not the same question. Last time Vi
said, "What's the best source of veg
protein without carbs?" Now she's asking
without fat and carbs.
Um, if you remove fat and carb, you're
left with protein. But there's no wedge
sauce like
that. There's none. See, that's the
ideal protein. It's just protein.
There's no fat, no carbs. That's what
you get from whey protein. So, I think
veg protein is I think whey protein is
veg protein, but it doesn't grow on
trees. It's it's a dairy product. So
what you do is when you when you're
making
curd when you're making curd you whey is
that watery byproduct which contains a
lot of protein. So you then somehow
process it and you get this powder which
is whey protein powder which is mainly
protein. Now it depends on the brand.
Some brands put a lot of sugar in that
and they say it's only 10% carbs but
there's 10% of sugar in there. You
should go with the clean flavorless whey
protein just white stuff. No flavor, no
added anything, just protein. So I think
there would have 20 25 grams of protein
per scoop or
something. That's the best source of veg
protein, non u non cruelty protein,
right? With no fats, no carbs. But if
you don't want any processed stuff, whey
protein obviously is processed, then
you're left with paneer, which has a
tremendous amount of
fats. So that's all I can offer you.
There's no other answer beyond that,
sir. Um
ma'am right Gagandepid Dutta says why is
while China is supplying weapons to
Pakistan why aren't we countering China
by giving Taiwan supersonic weapons or
giving them nuclear warheads because
we're not children you
see if we start
uh giving Taiwan stuff then China will
no longer hold back in giving Pakistan
all the advanced stuff. They will give
the J20 um quasi stealth fighter planes.
They will give everything that they have
at their disposal to Pakistan. They may
even send their army into Pakistan to to
bolster Pakistan. They can do it. So we
don't want to escalate things. We'll
keep things the way they are. The world
is already at unstable enough place,
tense enough place and whatever we want
to do with Taiwan, we can do it secretly
instead of doing it openly.
Maybe we are doing stuff with heaven.
But maybe maybe the citizens and
civilians are not supposed to know it.
See everything is not like what happens
on the TV news
debates and so on. Things happen quietly
behind the
scenes. So
please let's not have all these
expectations that everything will be
done in
public. There are relations between
India and Taiwan by the way. by the
way. Yeah, but we don't talk about them,
so I already said too much. Hush,
hush. Okay. Arian says, "If we send one
entangled particle into a black hole and
keep the other one under observation,
would information still be conserved?"
Is a good question.
Yes. Would information still be
conserved? No. That's not what I care
about. I want to know what's the state
of the other guy
inside. Information conserved. The
information is all right. So I have two
particles. I I've created a pair of
entangled particles. Okay, photons. Oh,
whatever with they entangled. So what's
entanglement? It's like we have two
gloves. It's a very crude example, not a
very accurate example. Let's say you
have two gloves. A left-handed glove and
a right-handed glove. You pack them in
two packages. I send one to Nairobi. I
send the other one to Moscow. My friend
in Moscow, Mr. Putin, opens it. He says
there's a left-handed glove. Is yes is
left-handed glove. So it means that Mr.
or whoever it is in Nairobi has received
a writing glove that is so far away but
immediately Mr. Bin knows what the other
guy has. That's entanglement kind of.
It's a very crude way of putting it. So
let's say you have two photons which are
entangled. It means what does it mean to
be entangled in the at the quantum
mechanical level? It means that their
state can only be described by a single
wave
function. Okay, it's a
composite system with a single wave
function. So then you have this pair of
particles that are described that are
intrinsically connected to each other.
And let's say I send one to Andromeda
and I keep one here. Andromeda is a
billion plus light years
away. But still I will kind of know
what's the state of the thing despite it
being so far away that I can't access it
through light speed travel for 5 billion
years or something. So that's what
entanglement is. So now let's say we
take one of these entangle entangled
particles and send it inside the black
hole. There it goes. So will we know
What's the state of the particle? We may
actually that's a good thought
experiment. We keep the other one under
observation. What information still be
conserved? What happens? Will we
actually know? We will know what happens
to the other guy as long as the other
guy exists and doesn't become pure
energy. Um so this is the question
you're asking is not actually related to
conservation of uh um the the
information thing. It's uh more about
quantum mechanical
entanglement. So as long as the other
particle remains in existence inside the
black
hole and doesn't get for some reason
converted into pure
energy then yeah you may kind of know
what's happening
inside. That's what I'll say. Rotan
Roshan, thank you very much. Thank you
so much. Diva Sharma says Vietnam,
Indonesia, Singapore, Israel still
sovereign.
Singapore,
Indonesia, Vietnam. Well, I have news
for you. We got to study some
history. Moit says, uh, that's why it's
said that we all made of stardust. We
are all made of stardust. We all made of
star stuff. They made of stuff that was
that was forged in
these stellar
furnaces, nuclear furnaces. All the
stuff within us, it was created in the
incredibly hot nuclear
furnaces that are stars billions of
years ago. And all of that is within us
today. Just imagine that.
So
yes, uh Rohan Zurja says Trump's
communic commerce secretary says India
Russia relations hurt us. I just did a
half an hour
uh segment on that. So watch that. Watch
that in the second episode of geost
strategy with Kabijit with Aijit Cha in
which I just covered this thing that
you're talking about for about half an
hour. Watch that please.
GGZs says, "Can India become a
presidential form of government like the
USAFA in the near future?" No, not
happen in near future. The current
politicians will not allow that to
happen. I feel the US UK system of
democracy in a large country is
pointless. Well, you're saying exactly
what I've been saying for a long time.
So, I completely agree with you, but
it's not going to happen anytime soon.
The current political system is deeply
entrenched
entrenched. All the current politicians
have come to power and they have all
benefited from the current system. Why
will they allow the system to go away?
Not going to happen. Even if it's good
for the country, they won't allow it to
happen because of their personal vested
interests. So, it's not going to happen
anytime in the near future,
unfortunately. And it's
sad.
Uh Senpai says, "Are foreign powers
undermining a Hindu family unit?" I
think it's the maybe there are foreign
powers doing it, but it's the uh it's
the overall system that's doing it. I'll
I'll tell you what the economic system
it's in India the economic economy is
such that you can do well in your life
only if you move to a major metropolitan
city. If you live in a major
metropolitan city generally what you
need to have is both husband and wife
need to work full-time in order for the
family to have a good salary and to have
a good income. Now if both husband and
wife are working then who's going to pro
procreate? Who's going to produce kids?
And if you have kids, who's going to
take care of them? Maybe you can bring
in your parents, the kids grandparents,
but then who will who will provide for
them? It's expensive. In big cities,
very small apartments exist. And how can
you keep so many people in the
apartments? So both husband and wife
have to work and all. So it's the
system, the economic system that is
undermining the Hindu family unit.
Imagine in India where you can earn a
great income no matter where you are. If
you go to the if you go to European
countries, if you go to
Switzerland, you can have a great
livelihood if you're living in a
reasonably big city. You can have a
great income and livelihood if you're
living in a small alpine
village. But in India, if you're in a
village, you are in
poverty. Imagine if you did not have a
situation like that. Imagine if you
could earn the same amount of money in a
city and a village. Then what it would
do is that the Indian traditional family
system would continue the extended
family which was very good. Then you
could have kids even if you were working
full-time and your parents or
grandparents would take care of the
kids. There would always be somebody to
take care of the kids. So that was a
great system. It's it's being actively
destroyed right now. It's not foreign
powers. It's the current system that is
doing it. Our own
system geopolitical dub. Thank you so
much. I really appreciate that. Thank
you sir. Mahesh Rani says do you do we
know if the Indian government is
investing in AI? We are we know that and
the Indian government is investing in AI
and I am way more in way more positive
and optimistic now after seeing recent
developments. Uh really now says would
one like living in China Tan Square
massacre. Today is the 4th of July 2025.
What happened 36 years ago? If you ask
somebody in China, they say, "What?"
Nothing happened 36 years ago. What
happened 36 years ago was a Thean Square
massacre. Brutal massacre. Would one
like living in China? Well, if you like
an authoritarian nation, genuine
authoritarian nation, sure, you'll like
it. Look, they have better living
standards than India. If you live in
cities like Hong Kong or or Shanghai,
it's first world standards. There are
other places where it's still like India
and so on.
But the system is authoritarian and if
you walk just one inch on the wrong side
of the law you'll you'll face the full
brunt of it. In India you can get away
with
anything. India India is a very very uh
relaxed country that way. Yeah it's it's
a real democracy and you have real
freedom in India. Believe you me once
you go out of India and live in some of
these countries then you will know what
real freedom is. So it depends on
whether you are okay with such things.
then you may just if you're okay with
living under a dictatorship as long as
the living standards are good then you
may enjoy China perhaps but the culture
is different
so Priy Chakrabati says why are tailless
fighter jets considered difficult to
pilots to pilot yet China continues to
develop models like the J36 and J50
look aircraft has traditionally have had
a certain set of uh certain kind of
design that ensures stability
So if you look at Cessna aircraft, old
ones and all, you can cut off the power
but they will still keep on gliding
under their own power. You take your
hands off the controls, the aircraft
will take care of itself. It'll just
glide. It'll just glide. It won't become
unstable. But when it comes to fighter
planes, you
deliberately in you deliberately have a
design that is unstable because that is
more maneuverable. But then for
maneuverability and control, you need a
computer, a high powered computer with
thousands, probably hundreds of
thousands, millions of lines of code to
control the aircraft properly.
Otherwise, it'll just tumble, right? So,
and and some of these fighter jets are
tailless and yeah, tailless ones because
they don't they lack the hor they they
lack the vertical stabilization. That's
why they are even more difficult to
control. For example, the the stealth
bombers, the big ones, they they're
shaped like boomerangs, like bats,
right? They have no tails. Super
unstable aircraft. They have very
powerful computers that control the
flight every millisecond.
Uh so yeah because of the physics
because of the the
um because of the the way the the you
know what do you call it fluid dynamics
aspect that's why they are so unstable
but they controlled by computers and
that's what and and because you can't
have such characteristics like a
vertical stabilizer when you want to
have stealth characteristics also so you
got to dispense with that but that makes
it more unstable. So that's why you will
need to develop more models like this,
more advanced models like this if you
want the stealth characteristics and the
other characteristics you want. So there
you have
it. Uh Ritikani says Russia being the
closest ally for us but do they still
have a spy network in India and vice
versa? If yes, then what for? Even
France and Israel too any major
self-respecting nation will gather
intelligence about its friends, allies
and enemies.
Everybody look why do you have embassies
in other countries? One of the main
purposes of an embassy is to collect
intelligence in Israel. If you are an
Israeli armed forces soldier, it is a
court marshal offense for you to accept
a ride from a vehicle that has foreign
diplomatic plates because all foreign
diplomats are regarded as spies
including Indian Indian diplomats.
So, Israel regards our diplomats as
spies. What does it mean? It means their
diplomats are also spies. By the way,
excuse me. Hello. Wake
up. So, my point
is if you look at it from a certain
perspective, all diplomats are spies.
All diplomatic staff and personnel are
spies. They all have different
functions, different specializations,
but they're all spies. They're all
collecting intelligence. Some overtly,
some legally, some illegally, some
covertly. So, everybody does it. That's
just the way the game is played. Even
your friends do it to you and you also
do it to your friends. And that's all I
will say about
this. All right, that's welcome to the
real world people. Let's open our eyes.
Let's dispense with the naive. The real
world operates in this manner.
Rahul Lakshmanan says, "What's the
status of the river in third linking
project? Is it a good idea on paper?
When will it be completed with a
probability estimate?" I have no idea. I
look at geopolitics. I don't look at
what's happening within India, whether
we are linking the rivers. Is it a good
idea? I'm not sure if it's a terribly
good idea. I'm not sure if it's a
horribly bad idea idea. It's a
reasonably good idea.
Look, one of the issues with river river
inter is that you know you may
cross-pollinate species that in some
cases in some rivers you have species
that are that are found only in that
river. Maybe it's a gigantic river so
it's big enough to have species that
exist only in that river but when you
start interlinking rivers you may have
that crosspollination which may not be a
naturally occurring phenomenon. So
you're kind of tampering with nature but
for the nation it may be very valuable
that sort of interlinkage. Um so I think
from a national strategic perspective it
it's I think it makes a lot of sense
probably. Yeah. But I am not aware of
the status of the project. I know it
exists. I've not looked into the status
and I don't know whether it will be
completed with probability estimate. I
have no idea because I know nothing
about it as of now. I would give a 50%
probability it'll be completed in the
next 10 years. I'm just saying because I
don't know. I think overall it's a good
good uh
idea. Bharava Pakum Pakamuri says India
boasting without shielding all
scientists. I don't understand the
question sir. What's the
question? India boasting what exactly?
Are we boasting that we have UFOs? Are
we boasting we have stealth submarines?
Are we boasting we have hypersonic
aircraft? Are we boasting we have the
world's best AI? What exactly are we
boosting? If you could be a little more
specific, sir, I could actually be able
to answer your
question. Uh, but I appreciate the fact
that you've contributed. So, you know,
next time please give a little more
details so that I I understand what
you're
saying. Uh, Arun says, "My dad always
said that if Indra Gandhi was alive, she
would have annexed Sri Lanka. Is it
true? Having Sri Lanka as a state sounds
good." Well, she was alive, wasn't she?
She was alive for a long period of time
and for a long time she was prime
minister. Did she enex
Lanka? Did she try annexing
Lanka? So look, I have not seen any
evidence of
that. And if she did not do it during
her, you know, lengthy life life
lifespan, uh, how do we know that she
would have done it
today? And does it make sense to annex
Sri Lanka at this point in
time when when the world is already on
edge? Why not just have economic and
cultural integration, reintegration with
with Sri Lanka? Kind of what we have
with Nepal without annexing it. Why do
something violent? Why not achieve the
same objectives in a very nice,
peaceful, mutually acceptable manner? We
should have the same arrangement with
Sri Lanka that we have with Nepal. They
are our own people. They look like us.
They speak like us. They talk like us.
They eat like us. They have the same
ancestry as us. Culturally, we
understand each other very well. We're
the same people. Just open up, right? No
visas required. Just walk in if you
want. Just the way we have with Nepal. I
think we can do that with Sri Lanka.
Then what's the need to annex the
nation? It's a wonderful, nice,
beautiful nation, wonderful people. Why
scare the hell out of them? Why make
them feel upset? Why make why give them
a grudge to hold against us? Just open
up, integrate the nation economically
and other ways and let them have their
sovereignty, but let them also be part
of us. That's the right way to do
it. Really? now says when no was it the
absence of divorce that prevented
polygamy to promote promiscuity in
ancient India or just innate values or
both what actually matters it was our
cultural values that pro that that
prevented promiscuity in India we do not
have that and we had provisions for
everything so
um usually most people did not practice
polygamy first of all
right most People just would marry once
one person in their life and that would
be it. It was generally kings who would
practice polygamy usually because it was
imperative for them to have many
offspring male offspring generally
because that's how it works. So it was
generally practiced only by kings. The
regular person would not have multiple
wives, spouses etc. Right? It was
just and it was a cultural thing. It was
a cultural thing. It's it's in value. So
it's allowed but it's not really done
unless you're a king and you need
multiple offspring because you know it's
a geopolitical thing. It's a question of
succession. You need to have multiple
options from where you can choose the
best possible successor. In that case
you can do that. That's how it was. So
it's or cultural values and so on so so
forth. And promiscuity was completely
unheard of in India. Of course you had
texts like the Kama Sutra and all. You
also had the fact that you know
prostitution was not illegal in India
but it was frowned upon very badly. So
it was not illegal it was but it was
regarded as immoral but it was still
allowed by the state. It was taxed
heavily and so on. So everything was
allowed in India but most people would
not do it because of our cultural
values. Okay. Uh Vic post again says why
don't schools teach Achara
Profulachendra a great chemist. Achara
Prulachendra a great chemist. his
students contributed to modern chemistry
and physics. Can you highlight his best
teachings? I'm afraid I can't I I'm not
aware of his best teachings. First of
all, I am I don't know much about
chemistry and I'm not really aware of
this gentle because I have never really
studied chemistry. I have not bothered
to
uh know about India's great chemists.
The one great chemist I know of is Dr.
Gotham Diu who has the highest number of
published papers and citations in India.
uh but let's okay I don't know nothing I
don't know anything about Acharia
Prulchandra but let's Google him and let
me do my best to quickly learn something
about him so
Acharia
acharandra
roy Indian chemist and educationist now
I always say don't look at Wikipedia
because it lies to you okay let's look
at West Bengal tourism what do they have
to say about achara roy
Okay. Okay. Indian government sites
don't open. That's lovely. So I'll have
to go to Wikipedia. Please remember
Wikipedia is not a reliable source of
information. I'm just doing a first pass
over here. He was an Indian chemist,
educationist, historian, industrialist,
philanthropist 1861 to 1944. The father
of Indian chemistry, Royal Society
honored his life because we need white
validation of course, right? Um etc. He
was the founder of Bengal chemicals and
pharmaceuticals.
uh family background, childhood
education, student in Britain,
scientific research, mercurous nitrite
uh for he for discovering nitrite
chemistry extremely effective
etc. crumbled this field for several
years. Long discipline etc etc etc.
Various chemical reactions that we have.
Okay. Revolutionary in the go of a
scientist deterioration. Okay. Social
reformer etc. Literary works. Okay.
Looks like a person who had multiple
interests. That is what you the the term
you use for that is is polymath. So
looks like it's somebody that is who has
done a lot of u interesting and probably
important work. I was not aware of this
gentleman. So thank you for bringing
this to my notice and I hope that
through through this medium more people
will go and look him up and maybe learn
about him and in case he's genuinely a
great uh Indian scientist then then
schools should teach about him. Schools
absolutely should teach about him. This
is the problem in India. We don't value
our people. We don't value the people
who have spent their whole lives serving
the country and and bringing bringing a
good good name for the to the country.
That's that's the sad thing about India.
viron school teachers because in the
schools the education system's objective
is to make people ashamed of being
Indian and to and
to you know give a big inferiority
complex to people. That's the that's the
objective of of the education system.
That's why it's that's why the situation
is the way it is. Uh Kiran Mida first of
all thank you so much. That's a very
generous contribution. I really
appreciate that sir. So the uh okay
what's please e please please ask your
viewers to watch his story of itas
well-made movie about how
Indian his history and education was
destroyed it's suppressed by the leftist
gang it needs support I'm not related to
the producers in any way sorry for hack
no that's all right please ask your
viewers to watch the the history of a
well-made
movie. Okay. So, yeah, certainly people
should check it out. I'll check it out.
What is the story history of itas? Let
me quickly Google it. Uh let's let's
quickly take a do a Google search. What
is history of? Let me find out. Uh
history of
it. What is this? His story of
Ithihas. Okay, this is the IMDb thing.
It's a true story about a physics
teacher who stands up against the system
to question the wrong and distorted
history of India taught to Indians for
generations in the schools. Well, sounds
familiar somehow. A physics teacher who
stands up against the system. It's got a
9.9 rating out of 10. That's
outstanding. 2 hours 24 minutes
2025. And u what's the review? Obviously
the reviews will be good and so on. And
who are the the actors? Arun Arun Vikal
Yogendu I think I've seen him before uh
Subod Bav Namya Saka Sachin Jaral and
other other people don't have
images and so on. Was Dama discovered
India. Yeah, I know this. Okay, sounds
like an interesting movie. So uh thank
you sir for for your contribution and I
certainly will check out this movie. Is
it available on in cinema houses or is
it available online? I'll find out and I
would recommend everybody do that. I'm
sure it's a great initiative uh to to
to bring this fact to everyone's
attention that our history has been so
so badly distorted and so on. So yeah,
thank you for bringing us to our notice.
Kiranji, thank you sir. Spade says Sar,
shouldn't India increase its nuclear
arsenal just like China which has
announced plans to add a 1,000 nukes to
add a,000 nukes by 2013?
We should increase it but we need not
necessarily announce it. Some things are
best left in the shadows. So yeah if the
Chinese are you know first of all how
many nukes do we have? The western media
says we have a what 170 nukes and they
say Pakistan has 165 or maybe we have
180 they have 170. They always want to
hyphenate India Pakistan. How do they
know how many nukes we actually have?
Have they come and checked or what?
Maybe we have
more. There have been studies done in
the past about how much file material
India has and it turns out that we have
sufficient file material. I mean we had
until around 2020 sufficient file
material for about 4,000 nuclear
warheads. Now some of it is locked up in
nuclear reactors. Some of it is locked
up in submarines. Some of it is locked
up somewhere else. But we still would
have sufficient facile material for at
least a thousand warheads, maybe more.
So look these things we don't discuss
these things the government never
announces the military never announces
these things are done are kept under
wraps but yeah if the Chinese are
increasing their arsenal there's no
question we should also follow suit
um really now says who has
is who has
is who has is tougher in the world today
okay who is tougher in the world today
India or China look who's stronger in
the world today China tougher. We have
existed for more than 10,000 years. We
are tough. We are tougher. But they are
stronger right now. Got
it. Arismanticor says according to the
science, absence of evidence does not
mean evidence. Absence of
presence. Okay, let me just wrap my head
around that absence of
evidence. The evidence is not there.
Does not mean absence of presence.
You're right. Yeah. So why do atheists
then say that God is not real without
proof? The the their imposition of this
belief on others seems religious. It's
it's
ideological. It's it's almost religious
in nature. Atheism itself is a it's a
religion. Atheism itself is a religion
by the way.
Um it's it's just another movement. It's
another religious movement of some kind.
But in this case, the the non-existence
of the non-existence of God is their
creed. It's their belief system. You
can't prove that God doesn't exist. The
same way that you can't prove that God
exists. Listen, you can't mix science
and religion, science and
theology. What is science? Science is
based on empirical observations and
physical objects in phenomena.
Now when it comes to God, when it comes
to the soul, atma, these are nonphysical
entities. The atma, the soul doesn't
have a physical shape or size or
weight. And
God is also not a physical object. It
it's something
else. So it is not part of the physical
world. Right?
So then if it's not part of the physical
world, how can you apply the laws of
physics and the laws of the universe to
these things? That itself is is super
stupid. But they are not intelligent
enough to understand how super stupid
they are that they're trying to disprove
the existence of God through the
physical laws. Super stupid. That's why
I say I've said this and I I apologize
to those who are offended, but atheists
are super stupid people. incredibly
stupid people. I mean, how on earth can
you make the claim that I know
everything in the universe? I know
everything about the universe that I
know that God doesn't
exist. How on earth do you know that?
How do do you even know what's beyond
the universe? of there is something
beyond the
universe. Making the claim that God
doesn't
exist is essentially making the claim
that I know exactly what's happening all
across the universe and beyond it which
to
my for me for a very small small
intellect by like me it's very stupid
really. Okay. Grock says universities
are producing mostly left youth left
youth leaders. Why? Because they're
designed to do that. It's by design
they're doing this. All
right. Um, Vidi says, "I Vidi says,
don't trust internet as much as I trust
you. So ask." Thank you, ma'am. Thank
you so much. I really appreciate that
and I gave you the best answer I
had. Gra says, "Please search China
non-uclear hydrogen bomb and explain."
Okay. Okay. Let's do that. China
non-uclear hydrogen bomb.
China
non-nuclear
hydrogen bomb. What is this? China tests
non-uclear hydrogen bomb. Science paper
blah etc shows white hot fireball
15 hydrogen- based explosive. It's a
hydrogen based explosive device. It's
not a thermonuclear bomb. 2 kilogram
bomb etc etc. More than 2 seconds 15
times longer
etc etc. key and magnesium based solid
state hydrogen storage portal. The
silver powder is magnesium hydide stores
contributed more hydrogen than a
pressurized tank. Okay, good. It was
originally developed to bring the gas to
off-grid areas. So, it was originally
developed as a storage system for the
gas because it it stores more hydrogen
than a pressurized tank. But then you
can use it for other purposes like
making a bomb. So, when activated by
convention Okay. Fine. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay, fine. Okay, I get it. Okay, long
story short, very very interesting, very
long. The main main thing is there is a
material called magnesium hydide that
stores considerably more hydrogen than a
pressurized tank of hydrogen. It was
originally developed to transport the
gas to off-grid areas by storing it
inside this material, the silvery white
powder called magnesium hydide. But then
geniuses thought, "Wow, we have so much
hydrogen, such a small thing. Why don't
we try setting it on fire or exploding
it? And then he discovered, wow, superb.
So that's the deal. It was supposed to
be a means of transporting hydrogen, but
then they turned it into a weapon. Every
technology has multiple uses, different
kinds of uses. It depends on who is
using it and what their per objectives
are. There we have it. Real analysis.
Could the big bank have emerged from a
singularity? Well, that's the standard
uh scenario, right?
If we we know that the universe is
expanding so we know what's going to
happen back you know far in the future
but if we just reverse the time and play
the tape backwards it means that we are
all contract the universe was
contracting so it it means the universe
was much smaller in the past and it kind
of implies that it started from a
singularity we don't know we don't quite
know if it was a singularity or maybe it
was something else but it started from a
very small almost pointlike structure
that's what it looks
Like Gagandit Deepa says, "H is useless
when it comes to building aircraft and
engines. We are 30 years behind China
when it comes to building fighter
aircraft. Shouldn't we privatize
H?" Um well, that's for the government
to decide. Maybe maybe privatization is
a good idea. Maybe it's a bad idea
because now then the government no
longer has control over it. Maybe we
should have public private partnerships
in which some things stay in the hands
of the government. some things become uh
are are done by private players.
Generally p private players they achieve
better results, faster results. Uh so
maybe the government doesn't want to
give up control over this entity. So
maybe
encourage private players to to enter
this industry, the arms industry and so
on. I think it's happening kind of. I'm
not sure if it's entirely useless, but
yeah, there are significant issues. No,
no question about it. No question about
it.
Um when it comes to fighter to aircraft
engines it's the GTRE that does it right
the gas turbine research establishment
Bangalore bang Bangaluru
um and they are developing the caviri
engine and they have done reasonably
good progress in that but we still
have waste
coal Ankita says doesn't Russia's slow
war strategy hasn't it been hasn't it
been proved to be severely
counterproductive giving Ukraine a plant
to such a devastating operation on
Russia when it could have flattened
Ukraine quite early in war. It doesn't
make sense to me what they're doing
really. Uh if I was Mr. Putin, I would
have finished the war in two weeks. But
then Mr. Putin knows better than me,
right? I think they have taken it they
they've let it let it meander for too
long and this has given Ukraine the
opportunity to because Ukraine is not
being uh taken over. It means that Mr.
Zilinski is now seen as more legitimate
despite him now being a dictator because
he is no longer the elected president
but he has imposed martial law and
because he has been in power so long he
has learned the ropes and now you know
Ukraine is able to use these asymmetric
beans to strike deep and hard in into
Russia thousands of kilometers away. So
if the Russians had overwhelmed Ukraine
in the first few weeks of the war and in
the first year of the war or by 24 2024
then these things would not have
happened. So it looks like it has proven
counterproductive. It looks like the
Russians want to just grind grind
Ukraine down and slowly steadily reduce
Ukraine's ability to fight against
Russia. But then these things happen and
the west keeps on supplying weapons and
they have given Ukraine the
authorization to use long range weapons
now which again could cross significant
red lines and so on. So I think it's not
a good strategy. I think it's been
counterproductive. It was okay for a
while but at the end of the day if you
have military objectives please go and
object achieve
them. Your military objectives and
political objectives are kind of tied
together. Achieve them and get on and
move on with life. So I think it's not
been a good strategy and it's it's yeah
it is what it is. So I agree with you
it's it's it's been significantly
counterproductive. The losses they have
sustained now I mean if it is true that
they lost more than 40 aircraft is it's
a disaster. It doesn't mean that they
cannot they can no longer deliver
nuclear warheads wherever they want but
it's a disaster anyway losing 40 high I
mean you know high value aircraft bad
very bad.
Saranj thank you so much appreciate it.
Thank you
sir. Arismicores what grade of AI do you
think was used in
opind military grade AI? That's what I
would say. Uh Tjasma thank you very much
sir. First of all a while ago after
Ratanta died you asked for you were
asked for your opinion on Mr. Tata but
you said it was too early to comment.
Can you please share your thoughts about
him now? I think it's too early to
comment. you know when um when Mr. Zia
lie of China he was asked by I think
kissing Mr. Henrik Kissinger or somebody
about his
opinion on the French Revolution. Mr.
Chamom said I think it's a little too
early to comment about
it. So I think I will I will I
will should I employ that strategy? It's
a little it's still too early like the
French Revolution. It's still too early
to know how how well it
went. Look, what do I have to say about
Mr. Utata? I think afterwards I spoke
about it. What did I say about Mr. Tata?
Let me just quickly see my own channel.
What have I said in case I have said it
then I don't need to repeat it over
here. Uh let me quickly go to uh let us
do a search on my channel in case this
is okay. So let us search here. This is
how you do it. Ratant
Tata. Did I speak about Mr. Ratant Tata?
Views on Ratant Tata five months
ago five months ago. So I I would s
suggest you watch this and uh that would
be it. But overall I
mean why would I ask you to watch that
when I'm over here live? So let me look
Mr. Tata was a great
uh industrialist entrepreneur all that
uh etc etc never married that's his
personal life I don't give a I don't I
don't care about that
[Music]
um but there are some problematic issues
he is known to have uh
funded uh academic research in the west
that is very strongly pro- India he is
known to have funded other uh
organizations media organizations
possibly that have
been disfavorably inclined towards India
etc. I don't remember the specifics of
it right now but yeah I the legacy is
mixed and kind of clouded in my
opinion what exactly were the things
which organizations did Mr.
of fund. Um let's let's go and
uh let's go and Google let's go and
Google
this. Okay. Ratan Tata funded anti-India
uh
organizations today
um Tata tapes controversy
philanthropic Tata trusts caught between
SCM Tata group funding anti-Hindu
activities in
India and so on. Po says Tata group is
international. So if you look into these
matters, you will find out that there
are
issues. There are issues. Okay, I don't
remember the specific details right now.
I had looked it up about 6 months ago.
But there are issues
unfortunately. So yeah, people like to
glorify individuals without studying
their activities in detail. Just because
the media is glorifying somebody, it
means it doesn't mean that you to jump
on the bandwagon and start saying ah yay
great sir, great sir, great sir.
There are issues with many
people. Jugen says the economic
trajectory of India and China was the
same up to 1991. Yes sir. But after 30
years China is manufacturing cup of
world. Do you think it's because of the
one party system whereas democracy is
messy in my opinion? Uh yes it is indeed
the case. When you are a dictatorship
you can get things done immediately or
almost immediately. You are obeyed when
you're a dictator. In a democracy, there
are checks and balances and there is
federalism and there's a separation of
powers between the center and the state
and a state has a different political
party. The center is a different
political party and they're opposing
each other and all kinds of
complications and messes. In China when
Mr. Xiinping says do this everybody
everyone does it then you have a much
more agile system much more responsive
system you can implement your decisions
quickly. In India it takes a lot of
time. There's a lot of friction. There's
a lot of inertia in India. China it's
smooth. That's why they are ahead of us
very clearly. So I agree with that.
Yes. Dext Dexter Laboratory says do you
listen to Achara Pashant? No sir. Never
never listen to
him. Wooden Armory PK says I have an
internet IT working in a fang
company. What should I do to ensure
livelihood 10 years down the line when
AI eats up all the jobs?
The only way you
will you will thrive in the age of AI is
if you learn how to become AI's master.
How to use AI instead of being afraid of
it. So, uh look, you're in a fang
company, right?
So, you you're going to learn how to use
AI in in what let's say let's say you're
a programmer, okay? It cool, you say. Um
let's say you are not a manager but
you're a programmer. So you are probably
developing or maintaining some software.
So what are the roles as a pro as a IT
You have a programmer or coder
who either creates new software or does
maintenance or you are a business
analyst who will talk to the business
folks and get the requirements and
create requirements documents, design
documents and so on so forth or you are
in the testing uh you know QA quality
assurance which is testing which means
you take the newly developed software or
maintenance software and you test it
against the client's requirements and so
on so forth. Now if
you
were think like a founder, okay, think
like a founder. You as a founder, you
have a number of employees who work for
you. Now when AI becomes good enough,
you will want to replace the employees
who are humans and who have deficiencies
with the AI which is more predictable
and powerful. So the question is if you
were a founder, how would you use AI?
How would you use AI to augment your
work and make it better? If you can
learn these
things then you will be one of the
managers of AI in a future company or in
a future uh time period. You will know
how to handle AI and how to manage it.
Then you will be one of the few humans
who has a job in an IT company but you
are managing AI employees. That's the
kind of thing you have to
do. Japan if offers jet engine for AMCA.
Will the US allow it? Maybe the US has
asked Japan to do that so that they can
insert some problems for India.
Uh Rohan Suna says, "Your views on the
Rosschild family, how powerful are
they?" I haven't studied these people,
so I don't know. U clearly they're an
old old money family, but I haven't had
the time to study their their family
history and uh they seem to be pretty
wealthy today. Also, it is alleged that
they are part of the what Illuminati and
deep state and whatnot. I don't know
about this. I haven't studied their
history so far. I haven't had the time.
So
sorry Ryik says why are Indians so
gullible and can be manipulated by
anyone easily and love getting validated
by west can they how can they come out
of their mental colonization it's this
inferiority complex thing right Indians
have a tremendous inferiority complex
because of so many things because of the
education system because of the media
because of the the role models they look
up to when the when your role models are
all sar of the west you will also feel
the same way and The education system
doesn't teach you how to see how to
decide what's right and what's wrong,
how to do critical thinking. So you're
gullible. You're going to be you're
going to believe nonsense. Then you're
going to be easily manipulated. So
because of these things, Indians are
gullible. Indians can be manipulated
easily. And Indians need they crave
western validation. How can you come out
of mental colonization? By learning the
truth, by by learning the true history
of India that we were never second to
anyone. we were the number one economy
and so on so forth and if if you develop
some self-respect and so on you will not
have mental colonization I personally
have never suffered from this problem
for whatever reason but I it pains me to
see Indians my fellow Indians uh be like
this it's painful sorry Barav says India
touts tech war but ignores scientists
okay that's the question you were asking
okay thank you so much for giving
details let's let's see India touts tech
India touts war technology technology
but in ignore scientist safety with
private firms in what precautions is
India taking to protect them 50
characters
limit okay okay I got it so we have war
technology but we are ignoring scientist
safety I've heard in the past that
Indian uh nuclear engineers or or
scientists or whatever some of them
allegedly it seems there were deaths
suspicious deaths and
Um I'm not sure what how true it is but
we know that Dr. Homie Baba was killed
in mysterious circumstances. Not a
natural death. His plane was crashed
into the into the Swiss or French Alps.
It was not found for 40 50 years. So
yeah, these things have happened
uh with private firms in what
precautions is India taking to protect
scientists? Well, whatever precautions
we may be taking or the government may
be taking to protect our our key
scientists, uh those will not be
announced and those will not be
publicized. So I can only tell you this
that I am hopeful that whoever the key
scientists are, we are taking all the
precautions we need
to ensure their safety. We've had things
happen in the past. For example, General
Bipin
Raat, he was a key uh military person
and we know how he how he died. We still
I mean I'm not sure if the report has
come out and it doesn't really matter
what report comes out because the real
truth will stay secret. So yeah, we got
to be careful about this. This is all
all I can say. I'm not in the government
so I'm not sure what precautions we are
or are not taking. I cannot tell you
because I'm not privy to that
information but I certainly hope we are.
I certainly hope we
are. Uh
Captain says are doing anything on
non-parmanu hydrogen bomb like the one
China tested recently. Don't you think
that would be more practical to have
than the classical ones? No. The
classical the classical ones cannot be
replaced by the one that the Chinese
tested recently hydrogen nitride or
something. The class the classical ones
especially the the thermonuclear ones
nobody can replace them.
Uh so I'm not sure if India is doing
anything about the non-nuclear hydrogen
bombs. Uh the technology seems to be
pretty straightforward. You have this
chemical which stores a lot of nitrogen
uh sorry hydrogen and you can set it off
with conventional explosions and then
the output is very nice very strong but
I'm not sure it can go to kilo to
megaton ranges I don't think it's going
to go to megaton kind of kind of yields
so that's why you can't replace the
thermonuclear bombs says followup what's
your opinion on Hindu lankan refugees
immigrants they don't hate us and are
integrated when compared to hateful ones
from the East. I have no issue with
Hindu refugees from Sri Lanka. Anybody
who doesn't hate us, doesn't want us
dead, who is okay, who is who is
um who is civilizationally and
culturally compatible with us, I'm okay
with that. My problem is
with those who want us dead. The 100
million Bangladeshes in India, they they
are not our
well-wishers. They have no allegiance to
India. They have no allegiance to our
culture or civilization. Those are the
ones we have to evict and deport.
Lankans, they're not going to do
anything bad to us. It's okay. We are
the same people anyway. So, I have no
issue with them. As Manteor says, I
don't get I don't really get with
right-wing or leftwing split. Why can't
leaders think about society's problems
and find a solution without locking
their flame frame of thought? Is it that
hard for critical thinking? That's the
problem with the political party system
that you are that you once you enter a
political political party you're forced
to align yourself with a certain
ideology. Maybe you you found that
ideology attractive initially you join
the political party but if you are a
well if you're a thinking person you'll
find that at least in the case of some
political parties the ideologies are
international then what do you do if you
have any sense you leave but I don't
know how it works. So the problem with
the political party system is that you
ali you're you expected to align with a
specific ideology. Maybe the ideology is
good in some cases but let's say you are
let's say let's say you're elected to
the parliament of India from so and so
con constituency. The people of your
constituency voted for you to represent
them in the Indian
parliament. So you are supposed to go to
the Indian parliament and represent this
group of people and you have to take
care of this group of people and
whatever their aspirations are, whatever
their problems are, you have to be able
to solve them from the parliament of
India. That's why you've gone there. But
because you are in a political party,
you have to ignore your constituency and
do whatever the political party's
leaders say because of party discipline.
Is it good for your constituency? You're
going to end up ignoring them. So that's
the problem with the political party
system. It's not ideal. You
see, Yashika says, "Is there a real link
between LOA and the cosmos?" Now, what
is
LOA? What is LOA? Let me Google it. L O
A. A god in the voodoo religion of
Heiti. Look, this is what I Googled,
right? L O
A. Okay. LOA and the
cosmos.
Eloa law of
attraction the belief that our thoughts
change of shape our experiences by
influencing the energy of the universe.
Look this is al what you would call
pseudocientific. I I personally am am
not aware of of any link between the law
of attraction and the cos
cosmos. Sorry sorry sorry. Uh Spade said
says did Neu Chacha push bach doi a for
Hindus by allowing Muslim
polygamy suppressing Hindu traditions to
undermine Hindu population. Should we
allow polygamy polyandry again? Is it
possible? Look Chacha
Neru I'm not sure I know about his
geopolitical blunders. I'm not sure
about other things. What he did
internally and what he did about the
Hindu Muslim dynamics and all. This is
something I am not aware of. I don't
study this stuff. I study geopolitics
history, the history from a global
perspective, not from the religious
perspective. There are many other
scholars who do that. I am not the
person to ask this question. So I don't
know what Mr. Nu did about the birth
rates of Hindus versus Muslims versus
any other religion. I'm not sure about
that. He was not fond of Hinduism. We
know that. We know that for sure. I I
would that much I know. Uh and I'm sure
that he would have loved to undermine
the Hindu population. That also looks
pretty
u plausible based on his uh proclivities
and his uh perspectives right uh should
we allow polygamy polyandry again look
our civilization our culture says that
has has nothing against polygamy or
polyandry I would say leave it to the
individual I I would say don't ban
anything just like we have unbanned
LGBTQ stuff whatever that is right we
culturally have never had anything
against LGBTQ people who ever existed.
Similarly, we have nothing. We have had
nothing. We've never had anything
against polyandry or polygamy or
whatever. We are a very relaxed
civilization. We said you do whatever
you want. As long as it doesn't bother
me, I don't care. So, I would say that's
the right way to that's the right
approach. Allow LGBTQ. Why? What's wrong
with it? If somebody wants to do it,
it's their problem, right? It's their
life. There's no right or wrong in that.
Similarly, if somebody wants to do
polygamy, let them do it. If somebody
wants to do polyandry, let them do it.
How does it harm society? It doesn't
harm society. So I would say allow allow
everything as long as it doesn't
infringe on anybody's rights, anybody's
life should be allowed. It's
okay. Air is manticores. Our focus on
multivariants of nuclear reactors. Why
depend on US and EU when they clearly
have no intention of allowing us
progress in this field? sodium, sodium
and other fusion reactors, variants,
etc. I think we are behind in our
three-stage nuclear program. We are at
the end of the first stage and the very
beginning of the second stage somewhere
like that. Um, and I'm not sure what
what the plan is. We should have a
completely indigenous system and the end
stage is we want to have thorium based
nuclear
reactors and we have the world's largest
reserves of thorium. So I don't think we
should depend on the US on EU on their
technologies. They obviously you are
right they have no intention of allowing
us to progress in this field. So we
should not depend on them. We should
have our own completely indigenous
program. If we can get some technology
here and there which will accelerate it
great but we should not be dependent on
anybody. Spade says please make ask to
ask sir. See this is why I've switched
to super chat so that I don't get such
silly questions.
But you managed to do it. Yes, I
appreciate I I
applaud I applaud your initiative. Naven
says, "Is karma real?" It's said to be
real. Could be real. I don't know.
Maybe. Why are some people born super
intelligent? Why are some people born
superior athletes? Why are some people
born handsome and some people not
handsome? Why are some people small and
weak? Maybe it's karma. What did they do
to deserve it? Not maybe karma. So maybe
karma is real. Who knows? How do we
know? It's
possible. Manticor says considering the
US the FE 404 may have must have been
tampered. It's possible. The engine
possible. Okay, I'm going to end this
very soon. So please stop with the super
chats. Please stop it. I'm going to end
this after two three questions. Jugen
says, "Should India consider to come out
of the UN, IMF, World Bank? These are
just useless submissive organizations.
In UNCC, Pakistan is a vice chairman to
counter terror organiz organizations and
sanctions. Look, there's no point coming
out of it and withdrawing. Be
everywhere. It should be part of every
scene. Be inside it whether it is
productive or not. As long as it doesn't
hurt you, be part of it. If it starts
countering your interests, then you can
leave it in protest. Otherwise, be part
of every scene. Be part of every room,
every hall where everybody else is
there. There's no harm doing that. I
know these are useless organizations.
The UN is useless. IMF and World Bank
are just US puppets. They are just used
for dueling out rewards to the to those
who provide services to the masters and
all. No, no, no question about it. UNCC
Pakistan vice chairman of this terror
thing. What
the very funny? There's no point uh
leaving it. Stay, stay, be part of
it. Nikil Shivasav, thank you sir. Why
is Europe called a continent even though
it clearly doesn't satisfy the
continent's definition? It's not a
continent. It's a joke. Calling Europe a
continent is a joke. Why is it still
called a continent? Because white people
think they are superior and they are
separate. So Europe has to be a separate
continent. It does not satisfy any
criteria of of the definition of a
continent. It's not a continent. So let
us not call it a continent continent.
Let them keep on harping about it. It's
clearly not a continent. It's a small
part of
Eurasia.
So let us not call it a
continent. Pravin, thank you very much
sir. Thank you very much. Captain says
there would be no radiation problem like
the classical ones and world sanction
would not apply on classical ones. So we
can't use it on neighbors. Look there
are there are
issues. You're talking about the
nuclear. Sorry. The nuclear versus
non-uclear hydrogen bomb. If you want to
deliver a
megaton class weapon to a
location,
then it has to be packed in a very
small volume, right? It should fit into
a nuclear warhead. It should fit into
into a missile fairing which has an MIRV
system which mean one which means that
one missile will carry five or 10
warheads and each of them has megaton
megaton kind of output. You won't be
able to achieve this with your hydrogen
non-uclear thing with hydrogen nitrite.
You will need much more like hydrogen
nitrate the powder. It won't fit into
this small fairing. The amount of energy
that can be output by a nuclear weapon
exceeds anything a chemical weapon can
do. That's
why that's
why otherwise you can use regular
weapons,
right? Uh Spade says uh chat and s keep
smiling. It looks Yeah, thank you. I
love smiling. I'm a very smiley smiley
guy. Thank you. Thank you. Arun says I
think Indians replace sab with sar when
talking in English to British accent.
Sab sab sar. Maybe it sounds similar and
it's used in a similar context. Very
interesting point you bring here. I have
not thought about it. Sab became
s. All right. All right. All right. All
right. Okay. Okay. I think we are at the
end of today's live stream. I have far
exceeded the amount of time. I was
supposed to do it for 1 hour but here we
have it. We are
done and I guess I will end the live
stream over here. So once again
everybody thank you so much for the
questions. I really enjoyed this. Going
to have another live stream tomorrow
night and then one on Saturday. So uh
please ask please please please keep
asking questions. Please keep learning.
Never stop learning. Keep raising your
standards and I will see you soon
enough. All right. Take care. Thank you
everybody. Bye-bye.